Bill Klinton Mendes Araújo

.NET Developer

GitHub: github.com/billklinton Address: Betim - MG, Brazil

Postal Code: 32675-876

Phone: +55 31 98885-9947

Email: bklinton14@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/billklinton

I'm a developer passionate with technology, trying to make people life better thru it. I build softwares since 2013, but professionally since 2018, I'm focused on the .NET platform, developing, testing and maintaining enterprise software applications. I have experience on building APIs, websites, mobile apps, workers and softwares in general.

Work experience

.NET Developer - InMetrics

07/2021 - Present São Paulo, SP

- Development of new systems and features for brazilian banks, using the following technologies:
 - Banco Neon .NET Core, RabbitMQ, Kafka, MongoDB, SQLServer, GoCD and Rancher.
 - Banco Carrefour .NET Core, RabbitMQ, SQLServer, Apigee, Jenkins and Openshift.

.NET Developer - ConferIR

02/2021 - 07/2021 São Paulo, SP

- Development and maintenance of the company's software (Rest API in .NET Core), which manages clients and their information on the Income Tax of each one of them.
- Maintenance of the company's legacy software, made with .NET MVC.

.NET Developer - Sinqia

10/2020 - 02/2021 Belo Horizonte, MG

 Development of new features and maintenance of company systems based on the .NET platform.

.NET / Flutter Developer - Donuz

05/2018 - 09/2020 Betim, MG

• Development and maintenance of software to perform integrations between the Donuz system and third-party systems, the integrations were made through Rest APIs.

- Development and maintenance of applications for Android and iOS systems, using the Flutter development framework.
- Publishing and updating apps on Google Play and Apple Store.

Technical Support Intern - Liga Sistemas

10/2017 - 05/2018 Belo Horizonte, MG

- Provide technical support to the clients of the company.
- Execution of database operations for data consultation, maintenance and troubleshooting with the system.

Education

B.Sc. In Computer Science, Falcudade Pitágoras 01/2016 - 12/2019

Technical Course In Computer Science, Senai Contagem 06/2013 - 01/2015

Skills

Back-End

- .NET
- .NET Core
- Entity Framework
- Dapper
- RabbitMQ
- Kafka
- MediatR
- Unit Tests

Front-End

- Angular
- Typescript
- Bootstrap

Mobile

• Flutter

Databases

- SQL (SQLServer, MySql, Firebird, PostgreSQL)
- MongoDB

DevOps and Others

- Azure Devops
- AWS
- Openshift
- Rancher
- Apigee
- Jenkins
- GoCD
- Heroku
- Firebase

- Docker
- Git
- Jira

Agile Methodologies

- Scrum
- Kanban

Languages

Portuguese - Native
English - Upper-Intermediate

Projects

Irmão do Jorel Wiki

Individual Project

05/2020 - Present Belo Horizonte, MG

The app and website shows informations about the caracters and episodes of a brasilian cartoon.

The app was built with Google's Flutter framework and the website was built with Angular + Bootstrap.

To look for the data, it consumes a Rest API in .NET Core with a MySql Database built by me as well.

Link: play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.devbkma.irmao_do_jorel_wiki

Website: irmao-do-jorel.web.app